<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Activities on Marko Vejnovic</title>
    <link>https://markovejnovic.com/activities/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Activities on Marko Vejnovic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markovejnovic.com/activities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SCUBA Diving</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/activities/scuba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/activities/scuba/</guid>
      <description>In 2017, around March, I was quite lucky to be able to enroll in a SCUBA diving course. I was required to remain physically calm, ie. control my breathing, even when my body would resist me.
In a sense, I&amp;rsquo;ve found it stoic to be able to control one&amp;rsquo;s body with nothing but reason.
But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. What I&amp;rsquo;ve found to be even more beautiful was that there was this whole other undiscovered world sitting literally a few feet under us and all it took to see it was to look in the right place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gliding</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/activities/gliding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/activities/gliding/</guid>
      <description>In the summer of 2016, I had the opportunity of going through basic training for a sailplane license. Not only was this by far the best experience in my life (being an admirer of planes since childhood), but this activity has helped me hone many skills - remaining calm in the face of apparent danger, and patience, being the two most important ones.
I experienced true freedom - lifting myself from the ground and seeing the world clearly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fencing</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/activities/fencing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/activities/fencing/</guid>
      <description>In 2014, an Italian fencer by the name of Giacomo Fanizza came to my hometown to try and spread the fencing culture to a country which did not have it. He almost single-handedly managed to raise some interest and created a fencing club.
A dozen or so of us joined the club in the beginning, but as years went on, people started leaving. Sadly, Giacomo was forced to go back to Italy due to financial reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karate</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/activities/karate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/activities/karate/</guid>
      <description>In 2006, I was inspired by the likes of actors like Jackie Chan to pick up a martial art. My father saw a poster for a Karate club inviting new members, so I signed up.
At such a young age, I found Karate to be a very good practice for my body as well as a way of venting a lot of the issues I had inside and outside of school.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>