<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marko Vejnovic</title>
    <link>https://markovejnovic.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Marko Vejnovic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markovejnovic.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flashing a Chinese Phone</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/blog/flashing-a-chinese-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/blog/flashing-a-chinese-phone/</guid>
      <description>Introduction So, about three days ago, I managed to get my hands on a cheapish second hand Xiaomi Redmi Note 4. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really have a phone for almost a year, and living without a phone in China to be very difficult. I decided to buy a cheap phone on Xianyu.
Buying the phone After looking around a bit, I concluded that the Xiaomi Redmi 4X seemed to be a good phone for my requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fairs</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/fairs/fairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 11:42:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/fairs/fairs/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been (and hopefully - will be) presenting projects at fairs. These are some of my experiences with fairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troop &#39;em all</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/blog/troop-em-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/blog/troop-em-all/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A few mates of mine and I got back together in UWC. We decided to play for the first open mic1 of this year in UWC CSC. Given that three out of four band members enjoy metal, we decided to play metal for the open mic. This was a first for the school, since metal was never played on this campus. We decided for the first song to be a lighter one, so we decided on Maiden&amp;rsquo;s hit The Trooper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banjalucka Gitarijada 2018</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/blog/banjalucka-gitarijada-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/blog/banjalucka-gitarijada-2018/</guid>
      <description>Introduction After finishing up my ACT test and figuring stuff out after coming back from UWC Changshu, I get a ring from an old mate of mine who asks me if our old band would like to go to the annual guitar festival in my hometown of Banja Luka.
Our old band consisted of three guys - David Crncevic, Aleksandar Curguz and myself. We used to play metal, but since both David and me were going to UWC&amp;rsquo;s we couldn&amp;rsquo;t continue playing together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flying V</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/projects/flying-v/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/projects/flying-v/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Given my musical interests, I enjoy electrical guitars, and instruments in general. As I&amp;rsquo;ve never had a humbucker set-up guitar and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford one myself, I decided to make one myself. I thought it would be a great idea to actually learn some woodworking, since all of my woodworking experience prior to this was minor. Given that my father has already made two electrics guitar, I asked him to help me build it, but to teach me, rather than making it himself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Online</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/blog/website-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/blog/website-online/</guid>
      <description>Finally, after a prolonged period, I am publishing this website! Some of my projects are up, others are not, but, as time goes on I plan on adding more and more stuff here.
Sadly, I am quite busy to commit fully to this website, but when I have time, I will set it up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/projects/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 04:18:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/projects/projects/</guid>
      <description>Over the course of many years, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on quite a few projects. I&amp;rsquo;ve listed all of them here in chronological order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ikap</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/projects/ikap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/projects/ikap/</guid>
      <description>Introduction UWC Changshu China, the school I attend, has a single kitchen available to the students. This kitchen is shared between all of the students. The system for managing the usage of the kitchen (using paper forms) proved to be ineffective and overly complicated. I wished to improve on this design by implementing an online booking system. Currently, this software is hosted on ikcsc.site.
System The system is comprised of two elements1: a SQLite database and a Java2 application which handles database management and provides the frontend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quik</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/projects/quik/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/projects/quik/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I wished to write my own blog. To achieve this, I originally intended to use a custom markdown language for writing blog entries, which would support very niche requirements - dedicated citations, for example. Sadly, nothing ever came out of this as I did not really have a lot of time to dedicate to something of such high requirements. My blog (this one), ended up being written in Hugo, as that proved to be much faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tarpauline Kayak</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/projects/tarpauline-kayak/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/projects/tarpauline-kayak/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As part of the mechanical engineering 执行 1 in UWC Changshu China, we were making very low cost kayaks mostly out of PVC tubing. The original idea was for three teams to construct three different kayaks which would compete against each other.
Design I had the idea of using PVC tubes as a skeleton and a tarpauline sheet as cover for the skeleton. The skeleton consisted of 6 long tubes and 9 ribs which provided structural integrity:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INOST 2017</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/fairs/inost2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/fairs/inost2017/</guid>
      <description>On this year&amp;rsquo;s INOST fair, I decided to present what I was working on a few months already. I presented my system for making timetables for small aero-clubs.
Over the summer, in my aeroclub, we noticed that it takes a lot of time and effort to create chronometric tables (they are tables that a person is required to fill in and they contain basic information about a flight). We also noticed that it&amp;rsquo;s quite difficult to manage available aircraft and resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BlenderTextGenerator</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/projects/blendertextgenerator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/projects/blendertextgenerator/</guid>
      <description>Introduction During the HHG-Gymnasium BL MINT 2017 student exchange, the need for an application to quickly generate text in the wavefront .obj format for 3D printing has arisen. I have noticed that using Blender for such a simple task seemed to be quite overkill, so I decided to write an application over a night.
How It Works The application is written in python so that it can interface with Blender&amp;rsquo;s python API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Festival of Science 2016</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/fairs/fos2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/fairs/fos2016/</guid>
      <description>Similarly to the previous previous Festival of Science, I wanted to show science in a field that young children enjoy. So a friend of mine, David Crncevic, and myself decided to marry science and music.
Each of us made our own FuzzFace clones and we tried to show how exactly music is innately connected to science.
I&amp;rsquo;d say we succeeded - kids enjoyed our playing, as well as showed interest in science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tesla Fest 2016</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/fairs/tf2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/fairs/tf2016/</guid>
      <description>After not receiving any awards at the INOST festival of the year, I was invited by The programming camp Pitam Da to present my oscilloscope on the annual Tesla Festival in Novi Sad. Reluctantly, I agreed.
Contrary to my prejudice, it&amp;rsquo;s been an excellent experience, from hanging around with friends to actually presenting our own projects, we all had a wonderful and fun experience.
I did win a shared1 first prize on the festival, among some of my friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INOST 2016</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/fairs/inost2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/fairs/inost2016/</guid>
      <description>This year, I presented my Portable Android Oscilloscope which did not receive any awards. Overall, it was a fun experience to combine both software and hardware development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wah Wah Pedal</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/projects/wah-pedal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/projects/wah-pedal/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As an aspiring, albeit unsuccessful guitar player, I felt the need to have a wah pedal1. Of course, not having the resources to buy one forced me to build one. I wanted to achieve a Hendrix-like sound, so I decided to opt for a Vox V847A design.
Schematic The schematic is given.
The transistors I used were readily available 2N5457&amp;rsquo;s.
PCB Design Download The files (Eagle schematic and board layout) for the project are available at GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Festival of Science 2015</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/fairs/fos2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/fairs/fos2015/</guid>
      <description>The Festival of Science is a fair which tries to promote science with younger people. I decided to try promoting mathematics with middle-school students by introducing mathematics in the popular field of computers.
I decided that showing them basic TTL circuits, and how from these we can make basic calculators.
I then showed them how boolean logic describes these TTL circuits beautifully.
I&amp;rsquo;d say that the middle school students enjoyed this, because they like computers so I think it was good that I introduced mathematics (which is generally not popular) into a very popular field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INOST 2015</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/fairs/inost2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/fairs/inost2015/</guid>
      <description>Like the INOST fair the year before, I decided I would like to showcase my innovative products. This year&amp;rsquo;s INOST fair, I decided to showcase my Big Muff pedal, my Headphone amplifier and my Automated Camera Slider.
For the Automated Camera Slider, I was awarded the silver medal, and for the Big Muff, I was awarded the honorary award.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headphone Amplifier</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/projects/headphone-amplifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/projects/headphone-amplifier/</guid>
      <description>Introduction At the time, I used to have very high impedance headphones (if I remember - around 40Ω), so the audio output volume I was receiving from my computer was very low. I therefore wanted to make a small amplifier for those headphones. At first, I wanted to make a very simple LM386A-based amplifier, but I stumbled upon this small tube amplifier. I liked the idea of having a small tube amplifier, so I decided to make it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INOST 2014</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/fairs/inost2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/fairs/inost2014/</guid>
      <description>INOST is an exhibition of ideas, innovations and creations, where people from multiple countries gather to showcase their innovative or creative products.
Being a curious kid, my middle school physics teacher told me of this fair and how I could go. I did want to build something, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what exactly I wanted to make.
I came back home, talked to my dad and he told me that we would think about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Muff</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/projects/big-muff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/projects/big-muff/</guid>
      <description>Introduction One of my first major electronics projects was definitely the Big Muff clone pedal that my father and I worked on. At the time, I already had an electric guitar, but was looking for a more filled and warmer sounding voice. Given that we couldn&amp;rsquo;t really afford a guitar pedal, my father decided to build me one. However, as he was very busy at the time, he couldn&amp;rsquo;t really finish it, to which I asked if I could finish it, to which he obliged!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fencing</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/activities/fencing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/activities/fencing/</guid>
      <description>In 2014, an Italian fencer by the name of Giacomo Fanizza came to my hometown to try and spread the fencing culture to a country which did not have it. He almost single-handedly managed to raise some interest and created a fencing club.
A dozen or so of us joined the club in the beginning, but as years went on, people started leaving. Sadly, Giacomo was forced to go back to Italy due to financial reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karate</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/activities/karate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/activities/karate/</guid>
      <description>In 2006, I was inspired by the likes of actors like Jackie Chan to pick up a martial art. My father saw a poster for a Karate club inviting new members, so I signed up.
At such a young age, I found Karate to be a very good practice for my body as well as a way of venting a lot of the issues I had inside and outside of school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/home/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello! I&amp;rsquo;m Marko Vejnovic, an eighteen-year-old enrolled in UWC Changshu China. My interests are mostly in the field of science and mathematics, but I am not shy to open up to other fields as well. I plan on studying digital electrical engineering or computer science in college.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/license/</guid>
      <description>This website is licensed under the GNU Affero General Public License, which is given verbatim:
GNU AFFERO GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE Version 3, 19 November 2007 Copyright (C) 2007 Free Software Foundation, Inc. &amp;lt;https://fsf.org/&amp;gt; Everyone is permitted to copy and distribute verbatim copies of this license document, but changing it is not allowed. Preamble The GNU Affero General Public License is a free, copyleft license for software and other kinds of works, specifically designed to ensure cooperation with the community in the case of network server software.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>