<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Services on Marko Vejnovic</title>
    <link>https://markovejnovic.com/services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Services on Marko Vejnovic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markovejnovic.com/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Club of UWC Changshu China</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/services/pcuc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/services/pcuc/</guid>
      <description>In UWC Changshu, I heard that people were interested in programming. Rumor even had it that people were well versed in software development.
So I decided I wanted to collaborate with other people to work on some projects. I sent out a form and a staggering 60 people replied.
It&amp;rsquo;s time for the first class and no more than 10 people show up.
Since the people who came were beginners, I decided it was better to teach them programming from zero, so we agreed it would be best if they learned the C programming language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electrical Engineering Club of The Grammar School of Banja Luka</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/services/eecgbl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/services/eecgbl/</guid>
      <description>The electrical engineering club of The Grammar School of Banja Luka was founded in 2016. I founded it in hopes of trying to teach and spark interest in fellow students about electronics, and to an extent, programming.
It was somewhat successful, as there were half a handful of my ex-students who do electronics in their free time to this day. I had a both theoretical and practical approach.
I taught them how to make their own PCBs at home, how to solder and similar skills, alongside with the theoretical nature of electronics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>