<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Camps on Marko Vejnovic</title>
    <link>https://markovejnovic.com/camps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Camps on Marko Vejnovic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 16:54:06 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markovejnovic.com/camps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Camps</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/camps/camps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 16:54:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/camps/camps/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity of attending some courses and camps which are listed here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MINT Project - HHG Kaiserslautern, Grammar School Banja Luka</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/camps/mint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/camps/mint/</guid>
      <description>This project was a student exchange between HHG Kaiserslautern and my old school - The Grammar School of Banja Luka. The project was targetting students who were interested in and excel at mathematics, ICT, science, etc.
The goal was for stduents of HHG and The Grammar School of Banja Luka to work together to build a 3D printer, and present improvements for the printer, including solutions for problems. The printer was successfully constructed, but due to limited time, improvements to the printer were very limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petnica</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/camps/petnica/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/camps/petnica/</guid>
      <description>The Petnica is an independent institution of which the main goal is the development of scientific culture, scientific literacy and education in general. It offers week-long courses in various fields of science.
In 2016, after an application, I was invited to the winter mathematical-technical course of the institution. This course, I&amp;rsquo;d say, wasn&amp;rsquo;t special in any specific matter, but it did open my eyes to another way of looking at science and engineering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Pitam Da&#34; Camp for young software engineers</title>
      <link>https://markovejnovic.com/camps/pitam-da/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markovejnovic.com/camps/pitam-da/</guid>
      <description>The Pitam Da camp for young software engineers is a camp organized in my old school, The Grammar School of Banja Luka, for aspiring software engineers. I joined the camp in grade 10.
The camp was about teaching us useful concepts ranging from objective-oriented programming to threads. However, I found the course to be a tad too slow, Windows-focused and business-centered, which, at the time, I was not interested in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>